<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Jacob Moore</title>
        <link></link>
        <description>RSS feed for Jacob Moore</description>
        <atom:link href="/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                    <item>
                <title>On Stubbornness and Grit</title>
                <description><![CDATA[<p>I just finished reading Chapter 4 of Jeff Goins's book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Real-Artists-Dont-Starve-Strategies/dp/0718086260/"><em>Real Artists</em> Don't <em>Starve</em></a>. It begins with a quote from Jeff Bezos, founder of Amazon.com:</p>

<p>"We are stubborn on vision. We are flexible on details."</p>

<p>Goins starts the meat of the chapter with the story of F. Scott Fitzgerald, who persevered through hundreds of denials and rejections on the way to publishing his first novel.</p>

<p>Partially because of this perseverance, Fitzgerald grew into an incredible success, only to become results-oriented and focus too strongly on the critical and business reception of his work.</p>

<p>This led to discouragement and giving up.</br> 
Fitzgerald died at 44 of heart failure, mostly penniless.</p>

<p>Goins goes on in the chapter to define when exactly an artist should be stubborn and when they should not. The concept of grit is discussed at length.</p>

<p>I can empathize with discouragement and giving up. This kind of grit, pushing through adversity and failure for a longer-term view of success, was never something that I had to have.</p>

<p>My mom read to my brother and I from a very, very young age. The ability to take in and internalize new information grew from this learning. School was always easy, and when it got hard, I gave up.</p>

<p>In high school, I had a C in AP Chemistry. Partially to avoid difficulty and partially in an effort to graduate early, I dropped AP Chem at winter break and took on a much easier courseload.</p>

<p>This pattern of giving up when it gets hard has repeated itself several times throughout my adult life. I have been unemployed for over a month, and have taken on only a couple of new challenges. I have lost inertia. I wouldn't quite say that I'm depressed, but I have definitely felt rudderless.</p>

<p>I feel stuck between a few different paths:</p>

<ul>
<li>Continue to learn programming and web development, finding an entry-level job at a software company.</li>
<li>Pursue the artistic and creative dream of writing for a living.</li>
<li>Brush back up on DevOps-y things like Ansible and Puppet and find work in more of an IT capacity.</li>
</ul>

<p>I experienced the giving up pattern just recently. I was working on a website for the MtG league I run here in Wichita. After being away from the project a couple of days, I jumped back in and quickly felt incredibly overwhelmed by the amount of work that needed to be done. I gave up and dicked around for the rest of the day.</p>

<p>Even as I typed that last paragraph, I was thinking of solutions or strategies that I've heard or read or attempted to implement myself in order to solve those problems.</p>

<p>Grit, from my perspective, is a simple thing. Not easy, but simple.</p>

<ul>
<li>Show up, rain or shine.</li>
<li><a href="https://ryanholiday.net/life-as-a-grand-strategy/">Have a grand strategy.</a></li>
<li>Don't dick around.</li>
<li>Do the work.</li>
</ul>

<p>It's no more complex or noble than that.</p>

<p>Give some thought to this.</br> 
If you're experiencing doubt or want to give up, </br>
don't give up just yet. </br>
Consider another way forward.</br> 
Take the problem you're facing down,</br>
break it </br>
into smaller pieces.</p>

<p>How small?</p>

<p>This small.</br>
Two words.</br>
Maybe three words.</br>
Four if you must.</br>
Get specific.</p>

<p>Nearly every problem we face </br>
can be addressed</br>
with the right mindset.</br>
The right outlook.</p>

<p>The cliche goes</br> 
"The only person holding me back is me."</br>
This is both true and not true.</p>

<p>You are holding yourself back.</br>
But it's not all of you.</br>
It's the parts of you that are afraid.</br>
That are doubtful.</br>
That are hateful.</br>
Voices that you've heard and remembered.</br>
Voices that sound a lot like yours.</br>
Listen to them.</br>
Acknowledge their existence.</br>
Then move on with your life.</br>
Meditation helps.</br>
Silence helps.</p>

<p>Return to the bullets above.</br>
Show up.</br>
Have a plan.</br>
Don't fuck around.</br>
Do the work.</p>

<p>It's simple. Not easy.</br>
No one said this would be easy.</p>

<p>Back to the books for me.</p>

<p>Until next time.</p>
]]></description>
                <link>/life/2017/06/16/on-stubbornness-and-grit</link>
                <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <guid>/life/2017/06/16/on-stubbornness-and-grit</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Tech Midwest Lightning Talk</title>
                <description><![CDATA[<p>For <a href="http://techmidwest.org/">Tech Midwest</a> 2017, I submitted a five-minute Lightning Talk entitled <strong>Choosing a License for your Open Source Project</strong>.</p>

<p>The slides are embedded below. If there is video or audio of the talk, it will be added here.</p>

<iframe src="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1RYmkD6S1G7y2l0C025qQsW9-XW88xfXMsBG2XNwLbMQ/embed?start=false&loop=false&delayms=15000" frameborder="0" width="960" height="569" allowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true"></iframe>
]]></description>
                <link>/work/2017/06/03/tech-midwest-lightning-talk</link>
                <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <guid>/work/2017/06/03/tech-midwest-lightning-talk</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Don't Be Precious</title>
                <description><![CDATA[<p>I'm not very nice to my books. I dogear the pages, write in the margins, underline passages and sometimes break the spines (never intentionally). It's my quest in life to learn as much as possible, and my path to do that is littered with ruined books.</p>

<p>It wasn't always this way, though.</p>

<h3>Precious Books</h3>

<p>Throughout my adolescence and early adulthood, I revered books. I loved the way they looked on the shelves, the perfect smoothness of a well-handled spine, all of it. My time working at Barnes and Noble put me in the company of a lot of book people. They, like me, held a similar reverence for the printed word.</p>

<p>I looked askance at those who didn't take care of their books. Who didn't dust their shelves, who didn't write in a notebook instead of a margin, who didn't do any of the things I considered necessary for the curator of a library, or the owner of books.</p>

<h3>Homepage Woes</h3>

<p>Fast forward several years. I'm staring at the folder containing my personal webpage, my finger hovering over the delete key.</p>

<p>I want to keep it so badly.</p>

<p>But I can't. It's getting in the way.</p>

<p>I had spent the better part of the last week trying to integrate a statically generated blog onto the website. For a long time, I heard calls to start a blog from many of my favorite online columnists, and thought "That would be a good thing to do...on another day."</p>

<p>By the time I wanted to actually start a blog, my homepage sat before me, taunting me. I liked its simple look and straightforward design. I agonized for days trying to integrate a blogroll onto the site. I just couldn't make it happen, and it soon became apparent:</p>

<p><strong>I had to kill my webpage to move on with my life.</strong></p>

<h3>Get It Done</h3>

<p>There was no funeral.</p>

<p>In the end, I found a static site generator that I liked and applied a theme that I didn't hate. Kept most of the text from the original homepage for this new one, and moved on with my life.</p>

<p>It comes back to what many people have said, but in my opinion <a href="https://stackingthebricks.com/">Amy Hoy</a> said it best:</p>

<p>Just. Fucking. Ship.</p>

<p>I can tell you from personal experience that you're going to waste an inordinate amount of time and energy trying to make your way around all of these barriers you've set up for yourself.</p>

<p>Instead, consider just shipping. Get something done. Get your energy back.</p>

<p>Move on with your life.</p>
]]></description>
                <link>/life/2017/05/26/dont-be-precious</link>
                <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <guid>/life/2017/05/26/dont-be-precious</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>CSS: Center Multiple Lines on a Shared Character</title>
                <description><![CDATA[<p>In my work sprucing up <a href="http://collegehillcreative.com/">College Hill Creative</a>'s homepage, I discovered something that bothered me at the bottom of each page. The roster was formatted like so:</p>

<pre><code class="html">&lt;p style="text-align: center"&gt;
    Name Number One | Title Number One&lt;br/&gt;
    Slightly Shorter | Shorter Title&lt;br/&gt;
    Tiny | Tiny&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>It rendered like this:</p>

<p style="text-align: center">
    Name Number One | Title Number One<br/>
    Slightly Shorter | Shorter Title<br/>
    Tiny | Tiny<br/>
</p>

<p>The fact that the text wasn't centered on the pipes bothered me significantly, and I went to work trying to fix the issue.</p>

<p>My initial searches led me to attempt to maintain whitespace inside of the p element. This got close, but was too finicky and lacked precision. After spending some additional time trying in vain to solve the problem on my own, I reached out to the <a href="https://devict.org/">devICT</a> Slack channel for help.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.barrettmorgandesignllc.com/">Barrett Morgan</a> offered the following suggestion:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>@jmmoore you might try wrapping each side of the pipe in divs that are 50% wide. Then right aligning one side and left aligning the other...</p>
</blockquote>

<p>He provided some sample code as well:</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="//jsfiddle.net/jmmoore/5Lp1Lq8u/embedded/html,css,result/" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0"></iframe>

<p>It rendered relatively close to the way I wanted but the centering still wasn't exactly where I wanted it to be. However, I took his suggestions and spent some time trying different margin combinations. After some experimentation, putting the pipe character inside its own classed div did the trick.</p>

<p>The final version that works is on JSFiddle, embedded below:</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="//jsfiddle.net/jmmoore/5suyaqto/embedded/html,css,result/" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0"></iframe>

<p>This doesn't strike me as a particularly elegant solution, so if you have solved this problem in a different way, please reach out to me on <a href="https://twitter.com/jmmoore_">Twitter</a>!</p>
]]></description>
                <link>/webdev/2017/05/25/css-center-multiple-lines-on-a-shared-character</link>
                <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <guid>/webdev/2017/05/25/css-center-multiple-lines-on-a-shared-character</guid>
            </item>
                    <item>
                <title>Kansas Linux Fest 2017</title>
                <description><![CDATA[<p>I wrote about the <a href="http://kansaslinuxfest.org/">Kansas Linux Fest</a> and my experience volunteering with them.</p>

<p>You can read about it <a href="/projects/kansas-linux-fest/">here</a>.</p>
]]></description>
                <link>/life/2017/05/24/kansas-linux-fest-2017</link>
                <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <guid>/life/2017/05/24/kansas-linux-fest-2017</guid>
            </item>
            </channel>
</rss>
